The beat itself is [__] really,
really cool.
>> Perfect.
>> [music]
>> It's a re-imagining of a song by the
Gravediggaz, which was a horrorcore
group from the '90s. There were four
members. The two most prominent ones of
them, Prince Paul and another one of the
greatest producers who's ever lived, the
RZA.
>> [music]
>> When you look up the original sample, it
is by Larry Williams Inner Crisis from
1974.
Also, what's interesting is the drums
from this track come from a song called
Hi-Hachi.
These drums everywhere in hip-hop,
sampled in 317 songs.
>> [music]
>> And this is what I love about this
record and what Tyler's doing on it.
Because even just rapping over this beat
from the Gravediggaz to then going back
all the way to these Larry Williams and
Lafayette rock band samples is like he's
placing himself in a lineage. He is
saying without saying it, I am a part of
this lineage. That history is kind of
just built in organically into this
record. Where he doesn't have to say it
all the time. He can just be it because
he is it.